Hi, this is Sean Hobson.
What we're talking about right now is using our forwards, our power forwards as passers in the offense.
And one thing you can have very valuable with our post players, whether it be power forward or a center, is if they are good passers, your offense is really going to move well.
And what I'm talking about there is when I feed, if he's post up on the block when I feed him, if he just stands with his back to the offense, he doesn't know anything that's going on behind him.
So what we like to do is we either like our post players to catch and turn to one side if he can or if he can completely turn and face up, if the defender drops off of him and he can turn and face up, that way he can see what's happening in here, and he can see to pass the ball.
So we're going to show you here real quickly what it looks like when I feed the post, and we've got a man that is cutting down from the wing.
When he turns and he can see that man, then he can become a good passer and he can hit the cutters, and it's going to open up our offense a lot.
All right, here we go.
Ball.
Good.
So you can see that he was able to give a cutter the pass because of the fact that he caught, he turned to the offense, and he was ready to become a passer.
It's going to make your offense flow a lot better.